So, from there, let's get this function ready to go
下面 我们完成函数
called print_prediction_summary.
print_prediction_summary
I'm going to say let's grab the movie name
我们将从 movies DataFrame 中
and I'm just going to go into the movies data frame to get that.
获取 movie_name
So this is the data frame that we were working with at the very beginning.
一开始我们使用的就是此 DataFrame
Basically, if the movie is equal to the movie_id that you give me,
如果 movie 等于你提供给我的 movie_id
I'm going to go in and grab that movie title,
我将获取片名
and so this should actually be movie_id is the name of the column.
抱歉 这个应该是列名 movie_id
If you need a reminder, let's just do.
如果不记得的话 再回忆下数据
So it looks like this.
表格是这样的
Basically, we're saying go in,
也就是说
pull the movie_id, and then give me the movie name back.
提取 movie_id 并返回片名
So this is saying go into that dataframe,
转到该 DataFrame 中
grab the movie_id where it's equal to the movie_id,
当此 movie_id 等于该 movie_id 时
and then grab the movie back from that dataframe.
则从该 DataFrame 中获取电影片名
So if we go into the movie name,
再看看 movie_name
this is just some fancy string stuff that we could do.
我们只是执行了字符串操作
I think it just made it easier to read.
使结果更容易读懂
So I don't know that you necessarily need to do this part,
这一部分不是必需的
but this made it easier for me to read the output.
但使输出更容易读懂
Basically, if you see this, replace it with nothing.
这里是将这部分替换成空字符串
That's what this is doing. Yeah, so both of these
这就是这部分的作用这两行代码
are just cleaning up the movie name.
都只是清理 movie_name
Instead, we could have just pulled the movie name to use
我们也可以直接提取要使用的 movie_name
and then for user and I'm going to pass this ID into this part.
for user...在此部分传入 ID
We predict a, and here's the rating we predict for the movie.
we predict a...括号里是预测的评分...for the movie ()
Then we're going to pass in the user_id,
然后传入 user_id
and then the movie_id, and then the movie_name.
movie_id 和 movie_name
So now we have this nice statement that says for user 8 we predict,
这个输出语句清晰地指出 对于用户 8 我们预测出...
and this should be prediction for the movie, should be like that.
这里应该是 prediction
So for user 8 we predict a 6.65 rating on this movie.
对于用户 8 我们预测出此电影的评分为 6.65 分
So now we have this nice statement about what's happening.
这个语句可以清晰地告诉我们发生的情况
It would be really useful to understand
如果能知道预测值的实际效果
how well our predictions are actually doing.
那么对我们来说很有用
So that's what we're going to look at next.
接下来我们将检验预测效果
So what we are taking in is the validation dataset
我们将从验证数据集中
which we're using here to pull that particular information from.
提取特定的信息
What we're going to do is we're going
我们将对某些行
to make predictions for a certain number of rows.
做出预测
So the prediction that we're going to make,
我们将使用 predict_rating 函数
So what this is doing is it's looping through each of these arrays,
我们将循环访问这里的每个数组
however many predictions we want to make.
并且循环这么多次
But we're going to loop through that many and we're going to essentially
我们将提供每项的
give the predicted versus the actual value on each of these things.
预测值与实际值
So for the first part, we're going to get an error.
对于第一部分...出错了
So for the first part, we're going to just make this prediction on six of these.
对于第一部分 我们将对这六项做出预测
So you can see that for this user on this movie,
关于此用户和此电影
the actual value is an eight and we predict it to be about a six,
实际值是 8 预测值约为 6
the actual is a nine, we predict it to be a 7.3.
实际值为 9 预测值为 7.3
This is pretty good considering how sparse our original matrix was.
这个结果已经很不错了 因为原始矩阵非常稀疏
These are all movies that we don't have any ratings for these users.
这些电影都是用户没有评分的电影
So it's pretty spectacular that we're getting anything.
所以能够预测评分已经很棒了
We'll notice that if we try to do it for seven, we still get an error.
如果检验前 7 行 依然出错了
So we try to do this for the first six and we were able
如果检验前 6 行
to make predictions for all of these.
我们能够对所有用户-电影对做出预测
But then when we hit the seventh user movie pair,
但是到了第 7 个用户-电影对
we get an error. It says that this is out of the bounds.
我们出错了系统提示这个出界了
So this last part is to write a statement
最后一部分需要你
about what you think happened. I'll give you a hint.
编写一个关于实际发生情况的语句我提示下
It again has to do with the cold start problem
与冷启动问题有关
and the fact that we're getting new users and movies
我们向测试集里添加了
in our testing set that weren't actually in our training set.
不在训练集里的新用户和电影